Eliminating Evil Since 1812.
The Brothers Grimm is a adventure, fantasy, action
film directed by Terry Gilliam.
Folklore collectors and con artists, Jake and Will Grimm, travel from village to village
pretending to protect townsfolk from enchanted creatures and performing exorcisms.
However, they are put to the test when they encounter a real magical curse in a
haunted forest with real magical beings, requiring genuine courage.
Wilhelm Grimm, played by Matt Damon.
Jacob Grimm, played by Heath Ledger.
Angelika, played by Lena Headey.
Cavaldi, played by Peter Stormare.
Mirror Queen, played by Monica Bellucci.
Hidlick, played by Mackenzie Crook.
The Brothers Grimm is a 2005 fantasy adventure film directed by Terry Gilliam.
The film stars Matt Damon, Heath Ledger and Lena Headey in a heavily fictional reimagining of the Brothers Grimm
as traveling con artists in Napoleonic French-occupied Germany, during the early 19th century.
The brothers eventually encounter a genuine fairy tale curse which
requires courage instead of their usual bogus exorcisms.
Supporting characters are played by Peter Stormare,
Jonathan Pryce and Monica Bellucci.
The film was a British-Czech international co-production,
with the film being shot in the Czech Republic.
In February 2001, Ehren Kruger sold his spec
script to Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM).
With Gilliam's hiring as director, the script was rewritten by Gilliam and Tony Grisoni
but the Writers Guild of America refused to credit them for their work.
MGM eventually dropped out as distributor but decided to co-finance The Brothers Grimm with
Dimension Films and Summit Entertainment, while Dimension took over distribution duties.
Gilliam often had feuds with brothers Bob and Harvey Weinstein, which caused the
original theatrical release date to be delayed nearly ten months.
The Brothers Grimm was finally released on 26 August 2005 to mixed reviews
and grossed $105.3 million at the worldwide box office.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, germany,
literature, brothers grimm, con artist.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.